# **Joseph Arias**

(703) 887-8575 · Manassas, VA, 20136 · <u>http://www.josepharias.com/</u>
arias.joseph.a@gmail.com <u>o github.com/Salsa-Dude</u> <u>in linkedin.com/in/joseph-arias</u>

Full stack web developer with a passion for building software that drives innovation and community. With experience in React, Redux, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails and Ruby, I've built social platforms focused on community-empowerment, architecture web applications, and created multi-page websites to help businesses professionally display their company online.

## TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Full Portfolio: www.josepharias.com

## SkillHub - Demo | Site | Github

Skill Hub is a community platform where people can find local mentors in the DC area to meetup. Users can take a class, connect with mentors one-on-one, or even teach a class of their own and become a mentor.

- · Developed a **RESTful Rails API backend** with endpoints for users (student/instructor), courses, course\_session, messages, reviews, and categories
  - · Implemented user interface employing React and Redux with CSS Modules and Semantic-React for styling
  - · Utilized Redux-Thunk to make asynchronous calls to backend for responsive retrieval of persisted Postgres data
  - · Used **JSON** web tokens to encrypt user data and password protect user accounts

# Tiny Home Parkway - <u>Demo</u> | <u>Site</u> | <u>Github</u>

Tiny Home Parkway is an online community marketplace for people to list, discover and book parking accommodations around the united states for their tiny home.

- · Developed a RESTful Rails API backend with endpoints for users (renter/owner), properties, leases, messages and reviews
- · Implemented React and Redux on the front-end for the most effective state management
- · Validated users and encrypted sensitive information using **JSON** Web Tokens

# Arias Fence - Info | Site

Design and Created a 8-page website for a local fence business

- · Created the entire UI from scratch using HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery and BootStrap
- · Implemented **PHPMailer** for the contact form
- · Configured HostGator web hosting server through FTP (File Transfer Protocol)

#### TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, PHP, SQL, CSS, HTML

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Ruby on Rails, Redux, Node.JS, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, JQuery,

Databases:PostgreSQL, FirebaseCloud & DevOps:AWS, Git, GitHub

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelancer Web Developer, Manassas, Virginia

January 2018 - Present

- · Design, code and modify websites according to a client's specification from layout to function
- · Ensures each website is easily found by the target audience and manages the online presence and brand of the company

## All American Plumbers, Manassas, Virginia

Plumber's Helper - July 2014 - November 2016

- · Assisted in the assembly, installation and repair of plumbing and drainage systems in accordance with state plumbing codes
- · Worked with hand tools, power tool and electronic test equipment

# **EDUCATION**

# Flatiron School (coding bootcamp) - Washington, DC - 2018-2019

- Graduate of immersive Software Engineering Program

## Northern Virginia Community College - Manassas, Virginia 2018 - Present

- Coursework towards an Associates of Science in Computer Science